<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crypto Maps with IPsec</title>
      <link>/posts/crypto-maps-with-ipsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/crypto-maps-with-ipsec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IPsec with Crypto Maps&lt;/strong&gt; provides a method for securing IP communication between networks through encryption and authentication. &lt;strong&gt;ISAKMP (Internet Security Association and Key Management Protocol)&lt;/strong&gt; establishes the &lt;strong&gt;IKE Phase 1 tunnel&lt;/strong&gt; used to authenticate peers and negotiate the parameters for further communication. Crypto Maps act as the policy framework that binds IPsec settings such as peers, transform sets, and access lists to a physical (sub)interface. When traffic matches the defined crypto ACL, it is encrypted according to the transform set and sent to the specified peer through an IPsec tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LISP Fundamentals</title>
      <link>/posts/lisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lisp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Advantages and benefits LISP provides highlighted in this post are &lt;strong&gt;simplified traffic engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;multihoming&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;overlay tunnel&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;AF over AF&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locator/ID Separation Protocol (LISP)&lt;/strong&gt; is an IP in UDP tunnel protocol that separates the identity of a device from its location on the network. It allows sites to create tunnels between them and identifies devices using &lt;strong&gt;Endpoint Identifiers (EIDs)&lt;/strong&gt;. Traffic then enters and exits the network through &lt;strong&gt;Routing Locators (RLOCs)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is Timothy Gayney. I&amp;rsquo;m an IT professional with over three years of customer service and IT/NOC Service Desk experience, passionate about technology and helping people solve complex problems. My background in &lt;strong&gt;Computer Networking&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Cyber Security&lt;/strong&gt; has given me a strong technical foundation, complemented by hands-on certifications including &lt;strong&gt;CCNA&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;RHCSA&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;CompTIA A+&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m currently expanding my expertise by studying for the &lt;strong&gt;CCNP ENCOR v1.2&lt;/strong&gt;, as I work toward advancing my career in networking. I thrive in environments that challenge me to learn, grow, and deliver reliable technical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;hyperlinks to labs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
